Two Enemies ... The Mob ... The Ultimate Showdown.
Undisputed is a action, drama, crime film directed by Walter Hill.
Monroe Hutchens is the heavyweight champion of
Sweetwater, a maximum security prison.
He was convicted to a life sentence due to a passionate crime.
Iceman Chambers is the heavyweight champion, who lost his title due
to a rape conviction to ten years in Sweetwater.
When these two giants collide in the same prison, they fight
against each other disputing who is the real champion.
Monroe Hutchen, played by Wesley Snipes.
George 'Iceman' Chambers, played by Ving Rhames.
Mendy Ripstein, played by Peter Falk.
A.J. Mercker, played by Michael Rooker.
Jesus 'Chuy' Campos, played by Jon Seda.
Mingo Pace, played by Wes Studi.
Undisputed is a 2002 American sports drama film written,
produced and directed by Walter Hill.
The film stars Wesley Snipes, Ving Rhames, Peter Falk, Michael
Rooker, Jon Seda, Wes Studi, Fisher Stevens, and Master P.
Undisputed was released in the United States on August 23, 2002.
The film performed poorly at the box-office and received mixed reviews from
critics; nevertheless, it later found success in the home video market.
It is the first installment in the Undisputed
franchise, which includes three sequels.
The film explores themes of prison, martial arts, showdown, prisoner, sports.
The tone is emotional.